Kamyab Rouhifar

Web Developer

Email: karouhifar@gmail.com Phone: 437-984-5385

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/kamyab-rouhifar</u>

Website: www.kamyabrouhifar.ca

Sep. 2019 - Present

SUMMARY

High-performing individual with a proven ability to establish compatible requirements with User Interface Applications. Highly enthusiastic and dependable front-end and back-end web developing professional with more than three years of developing modern web applications using Angular, ReactJS, NodeJS applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming C/C++, C#, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (jQuery), TypeScript, Python

Database MS SQL, MySQL, Oracle SQL, MongoDB

Frameworks / Tools Bootstrap, Django, NodeJS, ASP.NET MVC, React JS, Angular, React Native IDE Tools MS Office, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, MS Visual Studio, MS Visual Studio Code

Version Control Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps Server

Case Modeling Visual Paradigm, Draw.io

Cloud Platform Azure Web Apps, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Heroku, Netlify, Google Firebase

Operating System Windows, Linux/Unix

EDUCATION

Computer Programming and Analysis

Seneca College, Toronto, ON

Award:

President's Honor List Fall 2020, Winter 2021, Fall 2021,

Bachelor of Tech Software Development Scholarship Fall 2019.

- Completed web development projects using Node.js, React.JS, JavaScript (jQuery), CSS (Bootstrap).
- Installed the setup of Oracle SQL Community servers using C/C++, Java application on Windows/Linux.
- Utilized web applications connected to MongoDB server Database.
- Designed data structures, algorithms, and object-oriented programming in the exact specification

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

House Renting (Server-Side Web applications using Node.js and Express)

Duration: Four months

- Created JavaScript ES6 web pages for administrator, user, and visitor's interface.
- Used HTML 5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript, Node.JS, Express and the Handlebars templating engine.
- Developed User data access by MongoDB Database, Google-OAuth 2.0 APIs server.
- Implemented user authentication and authorization by using server status codes.

Covid-19 Tracker (Web REST API using ReactJS)

Duration: 30 days

- Utilized open-source JavaScript frameworks and libraries (React, jQuery, Bootstraps, GSAP, and Leaflet).
- Designed The concept (application) of front-end web client development for tracking Covid-19.
- Constructed a survey of widely used current front-end development environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CAP 2 Associate Sep. 2020 – Present

Walmart, Richmond Hill, ON

- Took responsible for the processing of orders and shipments according to company policies and procedures.
- Followed company package/shipping standards ensuring all customers received all online order pickups in excellent condition.
- Determined customer needs by asking relevant questions and listening actively to their response.
- Read and comprehend job orders and trained in picking, sorting, packing, and binning.

Full Stack App Developer (Internship)

Jun. 2021 - Sep. 2021

DoubleClick Lending, Markham, ON

- Researched and built a POC mobile app development by using React Native mobile application.
- Managed application requirement and project coordination through Azure DevOps tools.
- Maintained and administered GIT source code repository through Azure DevOps tools.
- Experienced in working with Angular 10 modules, services, directives, and dependency injection.
- Hold responsible for creating RESTFUL Web Services to serve data to the front-end application in JSON format.
- Created a custom responsive web application to robust a line-of-business web application using Bootstrap framework.
- Modeled UI/UX specifications for web/mobile platforms of the company.

CERTIFICATION

- CPR and AED First Aid certified.
- Electric Pallet Jack certified.